Gennaro Tedesco

Curriculum Vitae

Current Position

2023-present: **Team lead artificial and document intelligence** at Finlink, Berlin.

Responsible of a team of engineers and researchers implementing and integrating machine learning models and document intelligence into our software. We bring document classification and information extraction to our document platform and build software for banks and independent advisors to use. My role as manager is to ensure that company objectives are efficiently translated into our software, as well as to supervise the entire development and infrastructure process.

Experience

2021–2023 Tech lead data science, Billie, Berlin.

Team lead supervising development of machine learning services in payment and identification domain: payment validation, identification of suspicious buyers and credit risk. My role was to direct the entire development process, from the initial business requirements through the scientific phase of model development until service integration in our platform.

2019–2021 **Senior data scientist**, Billie, Berlin.

Introduction and development of the entire area of NLP in the financial domain to assess risk and detect fraud. Language model classification with general deep learning algorithms on structured text; time series analyses in the financial domain and test of hypotheses for statistical significance. Development and deployment of (internal) applications for business intelligence.

2016–2019 Data scientist, Leverton, Berlin.

Development of deep learning models in NLP with corresponding classification algorithms. Implementation of predictive models, time series analyses and hypotheses tests. Development of internal applications for business intelligence.

2015–2016 Data scientist, HelloFresh, Berlin.

Development of prediction and forecasting models for customers churns and acquisitions. Study of time series behaviours, network analyses, implementation of machine learning algorithms for classification and regression.

2014–2015 Data Analyst, Bank of America Merrill Lynch, London.

Academic Education

- 2011–2014 **PhD in theoretical physics**, Georg August University of Göttingen, magna cum laude. PhD thesis "Modular structure of chiral Fermi fields in low dimensional conformal field theory".
- 2005–2011 **Master degree in theoretical physics**, University of Naples, 110/110 cum laude. Thesis "Discrete quantum field theory of the gravitational field".

Projects:

- Author of several neovim plugins and command line applications
- Active contributor to neovim and other open-source projects and libraries
- Invited speaker for podcasts and meetups

Computer languages

Languages Python, R, Go, Lua, SQL, bash, awk, LATEX, Rust

Infrastructure docker, kubernetes, dvc, AWS, Azure

cli jq, visidata, sed, awk, GNU core utils

Monitoring Grafana, Kibana, Tableau, Sisense

Languages

Italian Mother tongue

English Fluent

German Very good

Chinese **HSKI**

Publications

- G. Tedesco: "Modular structure of chiral Fermi fields in conformal quantum field theory"; eDiss SUB Göttingen
- K. -H. Rehren, G. Tedesco: "Multilocal Fermionization"; Lett. Math. Phys. 103 (2013) 19 [arXiv:1205.0324 [math-ph]].

Unpublished material

- G. Tedesco: Introduction to the theory of connections on principal bundles;
- G. Tedesco: Generalised Efron's dice problem: simple solutions;
- G. Tedesco: R for data science:

Interests

- I play basketball and chess in my spare time (less often tennis and volleyball)
- I played a major role in a short film (available online) about cultural exchanges among different countries at high academic level